postnord.com 2019-08-29

# Privacy policy - PostNord

**1\. Introduction**

PostNord AB (publ) and its group companies ("PostNord" or "we"/"us") respect your personal integrity. This privacy policy explains how we collect and use your personal data. It also describes your rights toward us and how you can exercise your rights.

The policy applies to you who:

  * are our customer;
  * are a recipient of electronic or physical shipments (e.g. letters, packages or goods) that we convey;
  * visit our web pages, apps, platforms and social media ("Digital Channels");
  * participates in market activities, competitions and customer surveys; or
  * in any other way comes in contact with us, for example via our customer service.

Our objective is that you should feel confident that your personal integrity is respected and that your personal data is processed correctly. All processing of personal data within PostNord is in accordance with applicable data protection legislation. Within the EU/EEA, the General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR")[[1]](file:///C:/Users/NIFR0000/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/INetCache/Content.Outlook/YH4VLWNA/eng-Extern%20integritetspolicy%20Final%2026%20feb%202019.docx#_ftn1) applies and such national legislation implementing GDPR.

This privacy policy generally applies to our processing of personal data. If you, when purchasing our services or in any other context, receive a different information text regarding the processing of personal data, that information text shall take precedence over this privacy policy.

**2\. What is personal data and what is processing of personal data?**

Personal data is any information that directly, or indirectly together with other information, can be linked to a living person. This means that a range of different types of information, such as but not limited to name and contact details, IP addresses, contest contributions, choices and preferences, is considered personal data.

Processing is any action taken with the personal data, e.g. collection, storing, modification, processing for different purposes, altering or deletion.

**3\. What categories of personal data is processed and for what purposes?**

**3.1. When you purchase our services**

For example, when purchasing our services, we will process your name, postal address, email address, phone number, information related to the content of the shipments (letters or packages) and destination information. Where applicable, personal identification numbers, preferences, behavior patterns, and information on whether you are a legal representative, may also be processed.

Your personal data is processed for the following purposes:

  * To provide the services you have purchased in accordance with the agreement with you, including the service description and the specific terms of service;
  * To provide additional services such as access to PostNord's customer portal on which you can receive information about your shipments and administer power of attorneys for the collection of mail;
  * To process complaints and returns or when you in other cases communicate with us via our customer service;
  * For marketing purposes, among those marketing via mail, email and sms/mms (which you can opt-out from by clicking on a link in each message sent through email or sms/mms, or by contacting us via the contact details below);
  * To analyze and group visitors on our Digital Channels based on selection, prioritization and preferences (so-called profiling) in order to provide you with relevant and tailored information, recommendations, ads and offers;
  * To conduct customer surveys;
  * To prevent, detect and prosecute fraud and misuse of PostNord’s services;
  * To obtain anonymized statistics over the use of PostNord's services;
  * To develop, test and improve PostNord's services and the technical platforms on which they are provided; and
  * Provided that you have consented to it, to create custom audiences in order for us to send you customized offers and marketing on PostNord's Digital Channels. You may withdraw your consent at any time by using the opt-out tools offered on the Digital Channel where targeted marketing and advertising occur. If there are no such opt-out tools, you can withdraw your consent by contacting us at the contact details below.

**3.2. If you are a recipient of shipments (letters and packages) that we convey**

As a recipient of shipments that PostNord convey, we process your name, address, shipment information, information related to the content of the shipments (letters or packages) and destination information.

Your personal data is processed for the following purposes:

  * To convey shipments (letters or packages) to the correct recipient;
  * To process complaints and returns or when you in other cases communicate with us via our customer service;
  * For marketing purposes, among those marketing via mail, email and sms/mms (which you can opt-out from by clicking on a link in each message sent through email or sms/mms, or by contacting us via the contact details below);
  * To conduct customer surveys;
  * To obtain anonymized statistics over the use of PostNord's services; and
  * To maintain, develop, test and improve PostNord's services and the technical platforms on which they are provided.

**3.3. If you visit our Digital Channels and our usage of cookies**

Whenever you visit/use our Digital Channels, we collect information that you have chosen to submit to us, e.g. names, addresses, email addresses, phone numbers and other personal data.

We may also process information regarding your usage of our Digital Channels, such as transaction history and technical data relating to the units you use to access PostNord’s Digital Channels, e.g. IP addresses, unique device ID and type of web browser.

PostNord offers certain services which require access to information from your mobile device, such as your mobile phone or tablet. It could be photos, contact information, audio recordings and location data. PostNord will never collect such data, unless you have given your explicit consent hereto.

PostNord has places so-called “cookies” on several of our Digital Channels. Through these, information on how you are using the Digital Channel in question is collected. You can find more information on which cookies Postnord has placed on our Digital Channels, and how to remove these cookies in PostNord’s cookie policy.

Your personal data is processed for the following purposes:

  * To maintain, provide, test and improve our Digital Channels;
  * To be able to offer you support when facing a problem on our Digital Channels;
  * For marketing purposes, among those marketing via mail, email and sms/mms (which you can opt-out from by clicking on a link in each message sent through email or sms/mms, or by contacting us via the contact details below);
  * To analyze and group visitors on our Digital Channels based on selection, prioritization and preferences (so-called profiling) in order to provide you with relevant and tailored information, recommendations, ads and offers. It is possible that data from your use of different Digital Channels from PostNord and its group companies is merged for this purpose, and for the purpose of developing products and services;
  * To create reports, review the effect of marketing campaigns and create anonymized statistics regarding the usage of our Digital Channels;
  * For management, development and testing of our IT systems in order to secure that our Digital Channels upholds high quality as well as identifying and preventing security attacks such as viruses; and
  * Provided your consent, to create custom audiences in order for us to send you customized offers and marketing on PostNord's Digital Channels. You may withdraw your consent at any time by using the opt-out tools offered on the Digital Channel where targeted marketing and advertising occur. If there are none such opt-out tools, you can withdraw your consent by contacting us at the contact details below.

**3.4. When you participate in marketing activities, contests and customer surveys**

If you participate in contests, customer surveys and other marketing related activities that we organize, we will process, e.g. contact information, entries to contests, opinions, preferences and other personal data that you choose to submit to us.

Your personal data is processed for the following purposes:

  * To administrate the marketing activity, contest or customer survey, including communicating the outcome to you and paying eventual prizes;
  * To inform about and offer you new marketing activities, contests and customer surveys;
  * For marketing purposes, among those marketing via mail, email and sms/mms (which you can opt out from by clicking a link in each message sent through email or sms/mms or by contacting us via the contact details below);
  * To acquire anonymized statistics from marketing activities, contests and customer surveys, in order to improve our services; and
  * To maintain, develop, test and improve PostNord's services and the technical platforms on which they are provided.

**3.5. When you otherwise are in contact with and communicate with us**

When you are in contact with us via, for example, customer service functions, we process information related to your customer service request. If you are visiting or communicating with us through our social media accounts (i.e. third party platforms such as Facebook and Twitter) PostNord may receive information on your profile and your interactions on such platforms from the third party platform provider.

Your personal data is processed for the following purposes:

  * In order for us to communicate with you or administer your request through our customer service, email forms and our social media accounts;
  * To analyze calls and chat conversations in order to improve our communication and for your and our security;
  * To acquire anonymized statistics regarding the usage of PostNord’s communication functions; and
  * To maintain, develop, test and improve PostNord’s services and the technical platforms on which they are provided.

**4\. Erasure of personal data**

Your personal data is processed only as long as it is needed to fulfill the purpose of the processing or to fulfill PostNord’s legal obligations. Thereafter, your personal data is erased in accordance with our erasure policy or internal guidelines for deletion of data.

**5\. Legal basis for our processing of your personal data**

PostNord will always adhere to applicable data protection legislation when processing your personal data. We process your personal data when this is necessary in order to perform an agreement with you or to respond to a customer service request you have made, or when we have a legitimate and compelling interest for processing your personal data, e.g. an interest to market ourselves to visitors of our Digital Channels or an interest in developing and improving our services. We may also process your personal data when we are legally obliged to do so.

Would PostNord’s processing of your personal data require your consent according to applicable data protection legislation, we will obtain your prior consent to such processing, which is normally done by having you actively tick a box.

**6\. Security measures for protection of personal data**

A high level of security for your personal data is of utmost importance to PostNord, and we have in place appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect your personal data from unauthorized access, modification, dissemination or destruction.

PostNord’s duty of confidentiality as set forth in the Swedish Postal Services Act, applies to mail, but other information about PostNord’s customers is also treated confidentially. Address information in our directory for mail delivery may in some instances be handed over to authorities based on an obligation in law or other regulation.

**7\. Limitations in the transfer of personal data**

PostNord may engage external partners and suppliers to perform services on behalf of PostNord, e.g. to provide IT services, payment services or to assist in marketing, analysis or statistics. The performance of these services may entail such parties, both within and outside of the EU/EEA, obtaining access to your personal data.

Companies which are processing personal data on behalf of PostNord are obliged to sign an agreement with PostNord in order to ensure a high level of protection for your personal data. For partners located outside the EU/EEA, additional protective measures are undertaken, e.g. the signing of an agreement which includes the European Commission’s model clauses for data transfers, which can be found on the European Commission’s website.

PostNord may transfer personal data to a third party, such as the police or other authority, in the course of an investigation or otherwise when so obliged by law or governmental decision.

**8\. External links**

This integrity policy applies to information that PostNord is processing about you within the scope of our Digital Channels. PostNord’s Digital Channels may sometimes contain links to external websites or services which are not controlled by PostNord. If you follow a link to an external website, you are urged to review the principles for data processing and cookies applicable to the website in question.

**9\. Processing of personal data concerning children**

PostNord’s Digital Channels are not intended for children and PostNord is thereby not knowingly collecting personal data pertaining to children. If you are a legal guardian and learns that your child has submitted personal data to PostNord, we ask that you contact us on the address stated in the section 10 below so that you can exercise your rights to, inter alia, correction or deletion.

**10\. Contact information**

The PostNord entity specified in the terms of the service you use, in the Digital Channel you visit or in connection with any other contact with us, is the controller of the processing of your personal data. If you have questions about PostNord’s processing of your personal data, or if you want information on and contact details to the data controllers in other companies within the PostNord Group, please contact PostNord’s Data Protection Officer on:

PostNord AB

Data Protection Officer

105 00 Stockholm

Email: [dataprotectionofficer@postnord.com](mailto:dataprotectionofficer@postnord.com)

If you are a corporate customer, please contact PostNord’s customer service or your key account manager.

**11\. Your rights in connection with our processing**

You have the following rights in relation to the company that is processing your personal data:

  * Right to access (register transcript) – a right to obtain confirmation and information of the processing of your personal data;
  * Right to rectification – a right to have your personal data corrected;
  * Right to erasure – a right to have your personal data erased. This right is limited to data that, by law, requires your consent to be processed, if you withdraw that consent and oppose the processing.
  * Right to object – a right to object against our processing if the legal ground for the processing is based on a balancing of interests or if it is used for direct marketing.
  * Right to restrict data processing – a right to demand that the processing of personal data is restricted, e.g. if you oppose the correctness of the data. While the matter is investigated, PostNord’s access to the data in question is restricted.
  * Right to data portability – a right to request that personal data be sent from one data controller to another. This right is restricted to data, which you have submitted to us.

You are also entitled to, at any point in time, file a complaint with the applicable supervisory authority if you believe that our processing of your personal data is in breach of applicable data protection legislation.

If you wish to exercise any of your rights, or wish to acquire more information regarding any of said rights, or the conditions for exercising them, we ask that you contact us via the contact information in the section 10 above.

**12\. Amendments to this integrity policy**

PostNord may from time to time make amendments to this integrity policy. The current version of the integrity policy is always available on PostNord’s websites.

* * *

[_**[1]**_](file:///C:/Users/NIFR0000/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/INetCache/Content.Outlook/YH4VLWNA/eng-Extern%20integritetspolicy%20Final%2026%20feb%202019.docx#_ftnref1) _Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC._
